

# MEDIA ELMAS

**DATA ANALYST** 



615-668-9128



mediaelmas@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/media-elmas/



github.com/media94/Media-Elmas

# **PROFILE**

Data analyst with experience interpreting and analyzing data in order to deliver insights and implement action-oriented solutions to complex business problems. I have an excellent understanding of business operations and analytic tools for effective analysis of data. I am very excited and motivated to use my skills and education background as a data analyst.

# SKILLS

- Data Analysis
- · Microsoft Excel, Word, PowerPoint
- Data Storytelling Writing, Communication
- **Data Visualization** Presentation
- Organization, Time Management
- SQL, ETL
  - · Leadership, Collaboration
- Python Tableau
- · Problem Solving
- **PowerBI**
- · Bilingual, Kurdish

# DASHBOARDS

#### Where to Get Treatment Based on 2017 IPPS Data

Created an interactive dashboard that helps patients to find a healthcare provider based off of their location, cost, and experience.

This dashboard allows you to compare providers and cost depending on the desired healthcare services.

**Tools:** Tableau and Excel

Data: CMS.gov

**Link:** https://public.tableau.com/views/WheretogetTreatmentBas edon2017IPPSData/WheretoGetTreatment?:display\_count=y&:ori gin=viz share link

#### **Cardiovascular Disease Prediction**

Created an interactive dashboard that enables people to see the likelihood of cardiovascular disease based on their lifestyle, demographic information, and current health conditions. This dashboard allows you to visualize what risk category an individual falls into.

Tools: PowerBi and Excel

**Data:** Kaggle.com

**Link:** https://app.powerbi.com/view?

r=eyJrljoiYTI1NzNmYmltYjU2MS00OWZmLTk0ZjYtMzkwM2U5ZDN kYzÍxIiwidCl6IjEwMWRhNTg3LTE4NDMtNGY1Mi04YjhhLTE3YjA2O

WM2NmQzMylslmMiOjJ9

# **EDUCATION**

## **Nashville Software School**

Data Analytics | 2019 - 2020 Data Analytics Bootcamp

## Middle Tennessee State University

Master of Science | 2018-2019 Professional Science-Biotechnology Bachelor of Science | 2012-2016 Biochemistry

# DATA ANALYTICS EDUCATION

# **Nashville Software School** Data Analyst | March 2020-Present

Project-based curriculum using various data analysis processes and tools to clean data, explore and analyze data, build data visualizations to storytelling, while using SQL, Python, Tableau, PowerBI, and Excel.

## **PROJECTS**

#### An Overview of Healthcare Prescribers in the United States

Created a tool to display an overview of prescribers in the United States, and filter the providers to identify the suspicious ones. Used data from Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services (CMS.gov) which contains aggregated details of the prescription each provider gives. Providers who incur high cost when their patient risk score is low. By visualizing some important features, we can solve the problem of identifying suspicious providers.

## Data Analyst Jobs: Individual Project

ETL data from Indeed Data Scientist/Analyst/Engineer datasets on kaggle.com to provide an analysis for jobs posting in the data analytics field on Indeed. Responsible for utilizing Postgres SQL to create queries to help with data storytelling.

#### 'App Trader': Team Project

Collaborated with four other students to present to a fictional company called "App Trader," showing our recommendations on which Apps from Apple and Android app stores would they profit the most from. Responsible for analyzing the data using Postgres SQL, created visualizations on Excel to help with data storytelling, and used Google slides to connected out findings.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **Client Advisor**

**December 2018-Present** 

Louis Vuitton, Nashville, Tennessee

- Perform data analysis for employee productivity, monthly revenue changes, and identification of products on demand.
- Develop long-term relationships, leveraging different selling techniques to meet and exceed sales objectives.
- Achieved 135-150% of sales goal each month in the half year.

#### **Sales Consultant**

May 2019-December 2019

Tri-Star Medical LLC, Brentwood, Tennessee

- Market analysis on comparison of stores revenue and foot traffic, to provide insight on how to market the products to increase sales.
- Educate and advocate industrial hemp products.
- Promote and sell CBD products and network with other local companies.

#### **Biology and Chemistry Tutor**

August 2015-May 2019

Middle Tennessee State University, Murfreesboro, Tennessee

- Developed learning strategies which resulted in a 10%-40% improvement on grades.
- Taught studying techniques and time management for future application.

#### **Pharmacy Technician**

December 2017- April 2018

Cigna Health Spring, Nashville, Tennessee

- Used Tableau to visualize employee productivity and to provide analysis on claims.
- Managed pharmacy claims and verified insurance eligibility.
- Discussed pharmaceutical and medical treatment plans with patient and providers.

## **Administrative Assistant**

May 2016-September 2017

Siloam Health Center, Nashville, Tennessee

- Conducted new patients screening for refugee clinic.
- Validated insurance status to protect the organization and provide appropriate care for under presented population.
- Managed phone calls, emails, documents, scheduling, billing and coding.